https://apic.org/privacy-policy/

Topic-specific infection prevention
APIC Consulting Services, Inc.
Topic-specific infection prevention
APIC Consulting Services, Inc.
Privacy Policy
The Association for Professionals in Infection Control and Epidemiology, Inc. (“APIC”) respects the privacy of its members and other visitors (sometimes referred to together as “users”) to its website (the “website”). APIC has created this Privacy Policy to demonstrate its commitment to privacy and security. This Privacy Policy describes what information APIC collects information from users of its website, how the collected information is used, and the choices that users have concerning the collection and use of such information. Please read the policy carefully and note that by using APIC’s website, users signify their agreement to this Privacy Policy.
APIC may update this policy from time to time. Any revisions, amendments, or modifications will be posted on the website.  By using the Site after APIC posts any changes to this Privacy Policy, you agree to accept those changes, whether or not you have reviewed them, and such acceptance shall be deemed legally conclusive. If at any time you choose not to accept the terms of this Privacy Policy, you may not use this website.
What information does APIC collect and how is personal information used once it is collected? Most information that APIC collects is used only to help APIC better serve its users. In general, we collect the information that you provide to us when you register to use this website, when you provide us with information and comments through the site and when you send us e-mail. It is APIC’s general policy to collect and store only personal information that its users knowingly provide, and that APIC can use to improve the range and quality services to users of the website. Information collected online is usually defined as being either “anonymous” or “personally identifiable”.
“Anonymous information” refers to data that cannot be tied back to a specific individual. When you visit this site, APIC may passively collect other kinds of information through the website log files or cookies, including the location from which you visit us, the kind of browser you use, the date and time you visit the website, and the amount of time you spent viewing the website. Generally, APIC gathers this information for the purpose of analyzing aggregated trends and statistics. Aggregate data are only used for internal and marketing purposes and do not provide any personally identifiable information.
“Personally identifiable” information refers to data that tells APIC specifically who the user is. APIC does not collect any personally identifiable information from users browsing its public website unless they provide it voluntarily.
Users wishing to participate in any transactions through the website are required to provide APIC with a variety of necessary and personally identifiable information. In addition, to gain access to “Members-only” resources and personalization features on the APIC website, members are asked to provide limited personal information. APIC asks members to provide their name and member number for login purposes, and to verify contact information for abstracts, conference and meetings registration, and purchase of APIC products to obtain the discounted price. All of this information is submitted voluntarily.
APIC may store and process your personally identifiable information to better understand your needs and how we may improve our services, and we may use your personally identifiable information to contact you (for example, we may send you marketing or promotional materials or other information, we may respond to your comments or requests for information, or we may contact you if needed in the course of processing your requests). APIC may also use your personally identifiable information in accordance with any agreements that you may have entered into with APIC.
In general, APIC will not give or sell your personally identifiable information to any outside organization for the organization’s own use apart from APIC, or unless as permitted under any other agreement that you may have with APIC. APIC may, however, grant access to your personally identifiable information to groups that share similar goals with APIC, such as individual APIC chapters and their leadership, to the Society for Healthcare Epidemiology of America (SHEA), and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. Subject to applicable law, we and our service providers disclose and share your personal information among APIC and its business associates to unaffiliated third parties that are under contract to perform services for or on behalf of APIC (e.g., vendors hosting this website, e-mail fulfillment services, and the like), to a third party as discussed in “Transfer of Business Assets,” and to other persons as permitted or required by applicable law or regulation. Nothing in the Privacy Statement shall be deemed to prohibit APIC from disclosing your identity if APIC is required by law to do so.
APIC also utilizes NextRoll for our online marketing activities. If you live in California and would like to learn more about NextRoll and the California Consumer Privacy Act please click here.
What are “cookies” and how does APIC use them?
When you view the website or one of the advertisements on it, APIC may store some information on your computer in the form of a “cookie” or similar file. A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that is transferred from a website to the hard drive of a user’s computer. This unique number identifies the user’s web browser – but not the user – to APIC computers whenever the user visits the APIC website. Typically, a cookie will save things like a user name or other frequently used information that a visitor doesn’t want to re-enter each time they visit a site. The cookie file cannot be read from anywhere other than the machine it resides on, so there is no security risk in allowing browsers to accept cookies from the APIC website. A cookie will not provide personally identifiable information about users, such as their names and addresses. The use of cookies is now an industry standard and cookies are currently used on most major websites. Most web browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If users prefer, they can reset their browser to notify them when they have received a cookie. They can also set their browser to refuse to accept cookies altogether.
APIC uses cookies only to facilitate automated activity such as to store and track passwords. Cookies are not used to disseminate significant information about users over the Internet or to analyze any information that users have knowingly or unknowingly provided. For the APIC member, cookies eliminate the trouble of having to remember or re-enter passwords or member numbers. Cookies also help APIC to better serve its users’ needs and interests for subsequent visits to the website by customizing information on the APIC website to reflect individuals preferences and be most relevant to a user’s needs.
Why does APIC collect credit card account information and how is it used?
APIC collects credit card account information from users in order to process a transaction with a user made through the website. When members choose to use their credit cards, APIC submits the information needed to obtain payment to the appropriate clearinghouse in order to process the transaction. Except as needed to process a transaction, APIC does not disclose credit card account information provided by its users.
What privacy issues arise with links to other sites and who collects information and has access to it?
APIC’s website contains links to other third-party websites. APIC has no control over, and is not responsible for, the information, links, privacy policies or practices of such sites.
What types of security procedures are in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of information?
APIC will make reasonable efforts to keep secure the data you provide us and will take reasonable precautions, such as using a secure server, in an effort to protect your personally identifiable information from loss, misuse or alteration. APIC collects and stores credit card account information in an encrypted format. Although APIC endeavors to ensure the integrity and security of its network and systems, it cannot guarantee that its security measures will prevent third-party “hackers” from illegally obtaining information.  APIC cannot be liable for any security breaches, either by APIC or any third party, as discussed in greater detail below.
Will APIC be liable for acts of third parties?
Although APIC will use reasonable efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of your personally identifiable information, transmissions made by means of the Internet cannot be made absolutely secure and this website cannot be absolutely protected against unauthorized intrusion. APIC will have no liability for disclosure of information due to errors in transmission or unauthorized or negligent acts of third parties. In addition, APIC will release specific information about you to comply with any valid legal process such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute or court order. We will also release specific information in special cases, such as if there is an attempted breach of security or a physical threat to you or others.
Any information that is disclosed in public areas of APIC’s website, in online discussion areas, or on the Internet may become public information. Although we strive to protect our users’ privacy, we cannot guarantee the security of information you post in these forums. Users should exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information in these areas and disclose such information at their own risk.
May children use this website?
APIC intends that this site be used by adults and does not want to collect personal information from minors (children under 13 years of age, or any other age defined under applicable law). If a child has provided us with personally identifiable information, a parent or guardian of that child may contact us at the e-mail address or address provided by this website if they would like this information deleted from our records. APIC will use reasonable efforts to delete the child’s information from our databases.
What happens if APIC transfers its business assets?
As we continue to develop APIC, we might acquire, buy or merge with other businesses or assets. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets. Also, in the event that APIC or substantially all of its assets are acquired, both personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information will be one of the transferred assets.
How can users view or change their personally identifiable information?
You are entitled to request that APIC:
• provide you with a copy of your personal information that it holds;
• cease processing your personal information for the purposes of direct marketing;
• correct any errors in that information; and
• update that information as required.
If you have submitted personally identifiable information through the website, or if someone else has submitted your personally identifiable information through the website, and you would like to have that information deleted from our marketing databases, please contact us via e-mail at info@APIC.org or to the following postal address:
Association for Professionals in Infection Control and Epidemiology, Inc. 1400 Crystal Drive, Suite 900 Arlington, VA 22202
We will then use reasonable efforts to remove your personally identifiable information from our files, unless we are entitled to retain it pursuant to an agreement that you have entered into with APIC. You may also contact us through either of the above methods to request the personally identifiable information that APIC has collected about you through its websites. APIC will use reasonable efforts to supply you with this information and correct any factual inaccuracies in this information.
Questions about APIC’s privacy policy?
If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please write us at Association for Professionals in Infection Control and Epidemiology, Inc., 1400 Crystal Drive, Suite 900 Arlington, VA 22202 or send an e-mail to info@APIC.org.
Effective Date: November 2005
Member Services
About Membership
Join/Renew
Member Benefits
Chapters
Membership Sections
Publications
Infection Control and Epidemiology, Inc.
APIC is a 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization
CLOSE
